James **Benn**



Personal

James Benn Nationality: New Zealand YOB: 1987

About Me

I'm very interested in the analysis and geometry of continuum mechanics (in particular, the qualitative behaviour of PDE) and technical writing for science and engineering. I believe what's good for humans is good for AI and what's good for AI is good for humans: well produced and maintained technical documentation.

Soft skills

A curious and patient listener.

Very strong written
communication and
presentation skills.
A diplomat who leads by
giving people what they need
to perform.
Surprisingly entertaining... at
times.

Professional Interests

I'm a technical writer and research scientist working in mathematics, statistics and software for industry, and pure mathematics. I'm interested in statistics and mathematics for civil and software engineering, and producing and maintaining technical documentation of all kinds. My research interests lie in mathematical models of continuum mechanics and the geometry of diffeomorphism groups.

jbenn2@alumni.nd.edu

🌎 github.com/iksiri

C +33 7 84 79 03 77

EXPERIENCE

2020-now	Research Scientist INRIA · France ♥	lnría-
2019-2020	Senior Claims Analyst MINISTRY FOR PRIMARY INDUSTRIES · New Zealand ♀	MPI
2018	Sabattical - Visiting Researcher Bu-Ali-Sina University & Goethe University · Iran & Germany ♥	
2018	Construction & Maintenance Quality Control Analyst HIGGINS CONSTRUCTION · New Zealand ♀	
2016-2017	Postdoctoral Researcher and Lecturer Massey University · New Zealand ♥	MASSEY
2015-2016	Statistical Consultant MID-CENTRAL DISTRICT HEALTH BOARD · New Zealand ♀	

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Technical Writing Research Statistical Process Controls Performance Analysis Classification Time Series Random Forests **Decision Trees** Shape & Image Analysis Hydrodynamics Diffeomorphism Groups **Analysis** Differential Geometry Riemannian Geometry ODEs **PDEs**

PROGRAMMING

Python

R

SQL

LATEX

EDUCATION

2010-2015	PhD MATHEMATICS · University of Notre Dame, USA	
2010-2012	MSc MATHEMATICS · University of Notre Dame, USA ♀	
2009	MS APPLIED MATHEMATICS · Massey University, NZ ♥	MASSEY SHITSHIT
2006-2009	Bachelor Degree INFORMATION SCIENCE · Massey University, NZ ♥	HAMMAN MASSEY MASSEY

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

2024	Knotted Solutions to the Euler Equations on the 3-Sphere	2021/2022	Introduction to Riemannian Geometry (Graduate Course).
2023	Towards a BCH Formula on the Diffeo- morphism Group with a Right-Invariant Metric	2016	Mathematical Physics, Applied Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, Abstract Algebra,
2022	A Setting for the Measurement and Analysis of Shape Conjugate Points on $\mathcal{D}_{\mu}\left(S^{2}\right)$	2011 - 2015	Mathematics for Engineering. Discrete Mathematics, Calculus I-III, Linear Algebra & ODEs.

TEACHING